Before we switch to the code example,
我们切换到代码例子之前
you defines the posterior in this way.
你已经这样定义了后验
You already learned that the tiny details that over
你已经知道了 这里的小 z
here are observation vector could be a lot of data,
是观察向量 可能数据量非常大
and we do not want to carry the whole observation history to estimate the state beliefs.
我们不想利用全部观察历史来估算状态信仰
The idea is now,
我们的方法是
that we manipulate the posterior over here,
我们现在利用这里的后验
such in a way that you get a recursive state estimator.
尝试得到递归的状态估算器
We have to show that the current belief over here,
我们必须证明 这里的当前信仰
can be expressed by a belief one step earlier and
可以通过前一步的信仰表示
then update the current belief only with new observation information.
然后只需根据新的观察信息更新当前信仰即可
We call this estimator the Bayes Localization Filter or Markov Localization.
我们把这个估算其叫做贝叶斯定位滤波器或马尔可夫定位
This will allow us to avoid having to carry
这样 我们就不用
around all historical observation and motion data.
加载所有历史的观察和运动数据
To achieve this recursive structure,
要获得这个递归结构
you have to apply probabilistic rules and laws like the Bayes Rule,
你必须使用概率定理和定律 比如贝叶斯定理
or The Law of Total Probability.
全概率公式
You already heard about this in Sebastian's Lessons.
你在 Sebastian 的课上已经听过
So, this should not be something new for you.
因此 这不是新内容
I will also teach about The Markov Assumption.
我还会教你马尔可夫假设
This involves, making meaningful assumptions
它可以对不确定的值之间的依赖关系做出
about the dependencies between on certain values.
有意义的假设
So our goal on the next steps is to define the posterior in a recursive way.
因此 在下面的步骤里 我们的目标是以递归方式定义后验
This means, we want to fill out this box here on the right side.
业绩是说 我们想要填充右边这里的方框
The first thing what I'm doing is,
我首先要做的是
I split a whole observation vector into
把整个观察向量分为
the current observations and our previous informations.
当前观察和之前信息
This is important to achieve the recursive structure,
这对于获得递归结构非常重要
as a reminder you see again the definition of observations on the right side.
小提示 在右边 你有看到了观察的定义
Now, we apply Bayse rule.
现在 我们应用贝叶斯定理
You already learned about Bayse rule and the previous lessons.
你已经在前面的课上学过了贝叶斯定理
And Sebastian already told you,
Sebastian 已经告诉过你
Bayse rule is the most fundamental consideration in probabilistic inference.
贝叶斯定理是概率推导中最基础的内容
The tricky part is here,
这里比较难的部分是
that you have more than one variables on the right side.
右边的变量不止一个
Which means you have to apply Bayse rule with multiple conditions.
也就是说 应用贝叶斯定理必须满足多个条件
Now my question is for you.
下面 我的问题是
Could you apply Bayse rule for the localization posterior?
你能为定位后验应用贝叶斯定理吗？
As a hint to assume the state xt is A.
提示一下 假设状态 Xt 等于 A
And the observation vectors that T is B,
观察向量 Zt 等于 B
and please do not forget the other conditions.
此外 不要忘记其他条件